<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Kerrie Mariah</title>
        <description>Narrating Nuance, Crafting Concepts, Sparking Solutions</description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:58:08 -0500</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 05:58:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Blurred Line Between Machine and Muse: The Emergence of AI in Writing</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Picture the archetypal scene of a writer’s desk: strewn papers, ink-smudged drafts, a quill or typewriter, and perhaps a glowing candle. This setting has metamorphosed over the decades. Today, alongside the modern tools of a laptop or tablet, there exists a more invisible, yet potent, assistant — Artificial Intelligence. The blinking cursor on the screen, once a daunting challenge, now represents possibilities as writers can summon AI to weave tales, craft arguments, or generate ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integration of AI into writing isn’t a mere transplantation of human skills into a machine. It’s the result of intricate algorithmic advancements in the realm of natural language processing. Machines, after devouring terabytes of literature and text, have begun to emulate the nuances, tones, and rhythms characteristic of human-written content. The AI-written prose of today not only passes grammatical scrutiny but can evoke emotions, provoke thought, and even induce laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, for all its prowess, AI’s role in writing is not without contention. Detractors argue that it lacks the authentic human touch, the lived experiences that imbue writing with depth and soul. Proponents, on the other hand, highlight its efficiency, versatility, and the democratization of content creation. Why struggle with writer’s block when an algorithm can provide a spark? Why labor over syntax when AI can restructure a sentence with poetic elegance?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this evolution is not a zero-sum game. The harmonization of human and artificial intelligence in writing promises a symbiotic relationship. Humans provide the context, the experiences, the moral compass, and the overarching vision. AI, with its computational prowess, amplifies these inputs, refining them into polished pieces or offering fresh perspectives that may have been overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/ai-article-1.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image of a woman typing at a keyboard&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Also generated by AI&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, a pressing question remains: As readers and writers, where do we draw the line? How do we ensure that the essence of humanity is not overshadowed by machine efficiency? And, at the end of the day, if the narrative captivates and the message resonates, does it matter who, or what, is the author?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those still mulling over these musings, here’s an enlightening tidbit: every word of this piece, from start to finish, was crafted by an AI. A reflection, perhaps, of the very future we’re hurtling towards — where creativity isn’t the sole domain of humanity but is shared, enhanced, and celebrated with our digital counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty neat, huh? Everything under the horizontal line here is written by yours truly, human Kerrie (but still proof-read by an AI for grammatical mistakes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used ChatGPT with OpenAI to create this article using the prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/ai-article-2.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image of text that I entered into a chatgpt prompt asking it to generate this article&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prefer to be kind, even if it might seem like extra fluff to the neural network since the system picks up cues from what you write, influencing how it interacts with you. I added the phrase “I feel that you’ve gotten to know me pretty well” as a nod to the idea that the AI might use elements of my style from our conversations to craft the article. On another thread with ChatGPT, I had the model read multiple pieces from this website to mimic my voice…but when it writes back ‘as if it is me’, it sometimes adopts a jolly honky-tonk attitude which I found hilarious (but not overly helpful).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found intriguing was that the four different times I requested a piece on the role of AI in writing, each ended on a note of hope and collaboration. While this article is impressive, I’ll soon be publishing some not-so-stellar work from ChatGPT that made me giggle. So, there’s no immediate need to fear our jobs being replaced! These AI models, while advanced, still operate based on well-established patterns. They often require oversight, understanding, and a touch of crafty finagling to produce the desired outcomes. But it does beg the question - who should take the credit for writing this piece? Me for crafting the prompt and harvesting the answer like ripe fruit? Or should the author credit ChatGPT and the millions of authors who came before that it took it’s training data from?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The images in this piece were generated using Midjourney. I plan to write a guide and provide an explanation about it in the upcoming weeks so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 08:01:35 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/the-blurred-line-between-machine-and-muse</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/the-blurred-line-between-machine-and-muse</guid>
                
                <category>coding concepts</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Gift of Coming Home</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As I’m cleaning my nest of a room and reflecting on what I’ll need to pack on my upcoming journey back East, I can’t help but think fondly and forlornly of the home I’m about to leave…again. Over noonday margaritas last week, I was telling my dad of my upcoming plans and he let slip, “What are you running from?” and it made me stop and wonder quite a few times since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’m cleaning my nest of a room and reflecting on what I’ll need to pack on my upcoming journey back East, I can’t help but think fondly and forlornly of the home I’m about to leave…again. Over noonday margaritas last week, I was telling my dad of my upcoming plans and he let slip, “What are you running from?” and it made me stop and wonder quite a few times since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/coming-home-2.gif&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;elsa gif ringing in my ear&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Hopefully this siren call won’t be my downfall&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe five years ago I was running away, but these days I can hear a siren call calling me out into the world. It’s a strange feeling as if I am supposed to be somewhere at a certain time, maybe it’s to give advice to someone’s next chapter in life, or to lend a helping hand to someone struggling in a rural town which would start an important chain of events somewhere down the line, or just simply to be an example of what not to do so others can learn from my mistakes. I’m not sure, but a year ago I promised to listen to my gut and the same gut that told me I needed to come home for a few months is telling me again that there is something out there that I need to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a beauty in living a life that is true to yourself and not for anyone else. In the past, I’ve lived for my boyfriends, their hobbies became my hobbies, their dreams I tried to co-opt. It’s a fate I see of many young women and I’m thankful that I had lived through a situation where the evil of losing myself far outweighed the small and infrequent joy of being with someone who didn’t value me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming home has been a healing experience for me in many ways. When you leave your home to go abroad, you are leaving behind your people, family, tribe, and familiarity. It’s not always a perfect happily ever after or adventure as it is often depicted in TV shows or books, but it is most certainly an experience that adds depth and perspective to your life, often through suffering. The suffering, and joy, of trying to find your way back to your bed in a place you’ve never been, of being completely and utterly anonymous among strangers, of re-building who you are in a new community, of realizing your pre-conceptions and ideals may not fit in this new place and need adjusting can be daunting and rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/coming-home-3.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Emily in Paris taking a selfie&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The TV show Emily in Paris is NOT a good representation of living abroad&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the pain comes from being away from home for so long that you’ve become derailed from your roots and foundation. That you have a foot not only in two different places, but two different identities, two different mindsets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I don’t like using the word pain because it has such a negative connotation. I mean a type of mental discomfort that I wholeheartedly believe we should lean into, the same a marathon runner leans into the discomfort of their training to improve. My fencing coach used to push hard in our individualized training, until I was sometimes puking or shaking with fatigue (often it was self-induced punishment for showing up to practice a bit tipsy). He used to say that if he could keep pushing my physical and mental boundaries in practice, then when it came ready to compete, I’d be comfortable in my own discomfort and have an edge on my competition. The more he could push my comfort zone, the wider that zone became. And I feel it’s the same in life; that if you orient yourself to the right path and right goals, listen and truly care for yourself, that these paths of discomfort are expanding your horizon and your sense of self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I find it funny now looking back on it, that when I first came home I couldn’t help but believe I was a failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feeling of failure had been haunting me since returning from Everest Base Camp and I had been trying to ignore it through copious amounts of drinking in Thailand and video games (MTGA). I was wanting to find anyone else to place the blame on for this storm cloud that hung over me, and when you go looking to place the blame, you can usually find something no matter how irrelevant it is. I felt a failure because I was unmarried, failed myself in my last relationship, had no children or upcoming prospects, I’d be turning thirty in 2024, had no active source of income, and on top of all that I was once again living at my parent’s house. So in all appearances I was the caricature of a good for nothing wash-out living out of my parent’s basement and I made the mistake of letting that negative voice whisper as Wormtongue in my ear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/coming-home-4.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;gandalf meme begone to wormtail&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly and surely the gloom lifted when I finally took the time to take my head out of my own ass. Everyone was struggling with their own battles and the idealized lives I had pictured for everyone else were nothing but hollow illusions. Being married meant I’d have to give up my hard-fought independence, having kids would limit my travel and hobbies, working that career job wouldn’t have allowed me to come home, and living with my parents meant I could spend time with them. I was able to change my own internal narrative of how I saw my own life. From seeing my friends and family, I got to see the beauty of being married and having kids but I also got to see how I am not ready for that, at least not yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got to see the beauty of my own freedom and it made me realize that if I indulge in deprecating self-talk, then I’d lose the ability to see the joy and happiness of my current situation. Dancing with older generations to classic rock at local get-togethers, enjoying the advice and joie de vivre of older (and many happily single) women, hearing the gossip at the sailing club I’m working part time at, and watching my mom get hit on when we’ve grabbed drinks, it made me all realize that life doesn’t end with marriage and it certainly doesn’t end at 35, regardless of what society might say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized that every stage of life has its moment to shine and that it would be a crime to not celebrate every day of what it brings. That the next stage of my life will bring change; a celebration of the new things to come and a funeral dirge for the things I’d have to lay to bed and there is nothing wrong with that. Each transition is bittersweet, I am still in the spring of my life when looking at the big picture, not the winter as I had previously thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, my self-imposed narrative isn’t of a ne’er-do-well deadbeat, but of a budding entrepreneur starting her own consulting company (freelancing software engineering work and voice acting with already a few clients!), traveling where she pleases, exploring new adventures, and following her heart. A woman who knows her roots, loves her family, and enjoys the gifts that each day brings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img height=&quot;100&quot; src=&quot;/images/coming-home-5.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Computer screen in georgia&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Couldn’t find a better backdrop to do some work for clients&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From seeing my little sister again, drinking morning coffee with mom, helping my dad in Georgia to install a ceiling, discussing books with my brother, watching trashy fashion shows with my sister-in-law, laughing with my godmom, grabbing drinks with my childhood friends who I also consider family, going dancing at the local super market with my mom and aunt, fishing and hunting with my uncle, and holding my niece in my arms, coming home has never felt so good.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 08:01:35 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/the-gift-of-coming-home</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/the-gift-of-coming-home</guid>
                
                <category>Travel</category>
                
                <category>Creative Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Becoming a Software Engineer</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Never in a million years did I think I would end up as a software engineer. That was the furthest thought from my mind when I went to my first day of university and signed up as a linguistics major. I imagined myself going to remote parts of the world to chase down and record dying languages, or being a translator for the UN - anything but corporate life.
 
Of course, those are dreams of a young naïve high school graduate and soon the realities of life made themselves heard. I remember going to one of my linguistic professors and asking him what kind of careers should I be aiming for with my degree. He laughed and said the number one career for linguistics majors was unemployment.
 
By that time, it was too late to change my major and I had big bills to pay that were already piling up with no obvious career prospects to aim towards. It was during this time that a friend mentioned the possibility of software engineering and it’s thanks to him that I discovered something that has driven my career ever since. The beauty of programming was that it didn’t require a degree I couldn’t afford and that I could teach myself as I continued to work my part time jobs to pay the rent.
 
It wasn’t until years later that I realized my high school dreams were too narrow minded; with programming skills, the world is your oyster and there is so much you can achieve. You can build the technology that records and parses dying languages, be part of a team that helps automate the translations at the UN, explore computational theory on top of being able to work almost anywhere with flexible schedules, and more.
 
I ended up with a small google Chromebook which had been jailbroken to run linux against its will, and a few programming textbooks, starting with Ruby on Rails. At that point, I had been working in a Cuban restaurant for a couple of years and so I would take the laptop and textbook to the restaurant with me, taking the early morning shifts to take advantage of the downtime to study.
 
Easy peasy I thought to myself, I’ll get a job in no time.
 
Wrong.
 
Becoming an adept programmer is hard and it takes dedicated time. Anyone who tells you otherwise is either lying to you or doesn’t know what they are talking about. It took me about two years from the day I opened my textbook of sporadic yet intense studying before I got my first minimum wage support role in tech and another two years before I got a job in a bank earning an adult wage. I do believe that if I hadn’t had work or school responsibilities those initial two years could have been shortened drastically, but it still takes time to absorb the concepts integral to programming and to mull them over in order to truly understand them.
 
Some days (especially when I was reading a C++ textbook) it felts as if I was hitting my head against the wall over and over again. At one point, I took my week’s spending money and placed a certain amount every 20 pages and wouldn’t let myself spend anything unless I earned it through reading. As much as I love technology now, at the time it was tough to push myself because the topics can be dull at times and changing the way your brain works, especially from a liberal arts perspective to a STEM perspective can be challenging and painful. But the metamorphosis waiting at the end was worth it.
 
To sum up so far: Teaching yourself how to become a programmer requires hard work and dedication You definitely will not enjoy every moment of it so prepare yourself for some slogs and find ways to reward yourself through the small daily steps Take advantage of whatever schedule life has imposed on you to study concepts and practice
 
The light at the end of the tunnel
Then one day, head bruised with banging it against the table with frustration, clothes nearly ripped to shreds with exasperation, close to giving up, you’ll experience a eureka moment. Suddenly, all those disparate concepts you’ve been filling your head with, all those early mornings or late nights trying to follow textbook tutorials and YouTube videos come together. The problem or sentence before you finally makes sense.
 
This is what I consider the first foundational hurdle, you’ve built your foundation and your way of thinking has slowly changed and now you can build. It’s still tough, and there will always be days where concepts go over your head the first time round you read them, but now, if you go slowly and cautiously, things you encounter will start to make sense, or at least you’ll now know what to google when you don’t know how to fix a bug.
 
This for me was when programming became less about earning money to feed my growling tummy and more about enjoyment. There’s a creativity in programming that once you get through the initial slog, can make it come to life and there’s a joy when you realize you can create beautiful things with just your imagination, hands, and keyboard.
 
So no, it’s not easy but nothing in life that is worth it is easy. I heard a fitness trainer once say that there is no magic bullet, no pill you can take to rapidly lose fat and gain muscle, no secret tea to get those perfect abs. At the end of the day, the way to get fit is through hard work and sweat, and it’s the same with programming. Your gym is your keyboard, your diet is reading, your exercises are in logic, and there will probably be tears instead of sweat. But I can guarantee, at least for me, it was 100% worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 08:01:35 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/becoming-a-software-engineer</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/becoming-a-software-engineer</guid>
                
                <category>coding concepts</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>